Choose your weapon.
The Expendables is a thriller, adventure, action
film directed by Sylvester Stallone.
Barney Ross leads a band of highly skilled mercenaries including knife enthusiast Lee Christmas, a martial arts expert Yin
Yang, heavy weapons specialist Hale Caesar, demolitionist Toll Road, and a loose-cannon sniper Gunner Jensen.
When the group is commissioned by the mysterious Mr.
Church to assassinate the dictator of a small South American island, Barney and Lee visit the remote locale to
scout out their opposition and discover the true nature of the conflict engulfing the city.
Barney Ross, played by Sylvester Stallone.
Lee Christmas, played by Jason Statham.
Yin Yang, played by Jet Li.
Gunner Jensen, played by Dolph Lundgren.
James Monroe, played by Eric Roberts.
Toll Road, played by Randy Couture.
The Expendables is a 2010 American action film directed by Sylvester Stallone, who
co-wrote it with David Callaham and also starred in the lead role.
Is the first installment in The Expendables franchise.
The film co-stars an ensemble cast of mostly action film actors, including Jason Statham, Jet Li, Dolph
Lundgren, Randy Couture, Terry Crews, Steve Austin, Mickey Rourke, and Bruce Willis.
The film is about a team of elite mercenaries tasked with a mission to overthrow a Latin American
dictator whom they soon discover to be a mere puppet controlled by a corrupt ex-CIA agent.
It pays tribute to the blockbuster action films of
the late 1980s and early 1990s.
The Expendables was released in the United States
on August 13, 2010 by Lionsgate.
It received mixed reviews from critics, with some praise for
the action sequences, and grossed $274 million.
It was followed by three sequels: The Expendables 2 (2012), The
Expendables 3 (2014), and Expend4bles (2023).
The film explores themes of rescue, sniper, island, martial arts, tattoo.
The tone is intense.